all right welcome to our live board
meeting we are still discussing
our foundational documents and going
through
our vision of mission although we're
trying to get that a little more
either concrete or nebulous picking one
and then moving on to the next part so
everyone would like to share
yes so um i was looking at some example
mission and vision statements um
[Music]
so uh let's see
it's funny these websites that i'm
looking at they don't have actually have
them
yeah they'd have impaired like nike is
the vision is bringing inspiration and
invert
and innovation to every athlete in the
world
and then the mission is create
groundbreaking sports innovations
make our products sustainably build a
creative and diverse global team so that
when they are actually listing things
out that's the one
i just started reading a new one and
it's different from the others that i
saw
um
so yeah our you know i i think it
you know we're getting hung up a bit on
terminology and all these terms
are a bit vague like mission statement
it means different things to different
people
um and in different contexts um
it's just not a very specific thing um
and so our uh
let me just um
[Music]
give you the wording and i don't know if
y'all could pull up the document i was
going to try and put it on to the new
collective document so we'll probably
move this stuff over to the new version
anyways so i suggesting for the vision
just
i wanted to take any terminology out
that is just internal to the game b
space so like omniwin
so my experiment of that was a world
where
abundant resources are available to
projects that have long-term benefits
for most
beings that seems to be a short word
the shortest way to say omni when
yeah i kind of like that i mean i i i
like the idea of trying to get
rid of that either not well understood
or contentious
terminology which i think that's both
and then in the same way the mission is
just a rephrasing that we
we facilitate shared resources for
projects that we have long-term benefits
that have long-term benefits to most
beings
um
yeah so and then after five weeks of us
going back and forth and figured it out
i like it
well it was just the genesis of whatever
what everyone was
saying so it took it took all of that to
get there
um and then so yeah in the
protocol uh love uh foundational
document they suggest a couple bullet
points which we don't have
um for the mission uh
but like ray was saying that could
probably work um
but it might be helpful if we kind of
do kind of say what is what is the next
adjacent possible
that we want to kind of start with uh
and and we do have some shared resources
and we started listing them out last
meeting so we have the
um did we actually list them out or did
we just talk about them
i mean we so like i think the the things
that i have
highlighted down below um sorry like
just
selected if you go up a bit
not like color but just like the text is
selected yeah there you go that chunk
there
is like to me that was the group of
things that we like
that those were the resources that we
were kind of talking about that we would
be providing
and there was some talk about do we want
to turn these into sentences or because
there's sub points of a larger sentence
is that fine um i think the main thing
is just
to unders like to have some examples of
what we're doing how it's phrased we can
hash that out but to me that was the the
things that we said that we're actually
providing was the the community so
that's you know the mentorship
camaraderie that type of thing
um there was the knowledge commons our
knowledge base as we're going and doing
research
even if this doesn't go anywhere that
knowledge can still be there and shared
with
with others uh the shared resources
right
like stream yards and stuff like that
like so we don't have to go out and buy
separate things that
did different people already have it um
and then
you know ideally at some point the
ability to actually fund some projects
and
you know the community posted their
their money together and decides where
they want to put
put that towards so
there's a slight difference between
existing resources and potential future
resources
so right now we have we have it
resources the wrong word is that well i
think it's
it are they organization resources or
are they just directly member resources
right like stream yard is my research
right no but but that that's also
difference between now and then and then
personal
or organization but we're only listing
the organization ones
right um so yeah so
i don't i thought we talked about them
but i guess we didn't list them so the
existing resources
would be the domain name the things that
we already have yeah i thought
that was on here that was down um yeah
well i was i went down to assets here
listed however um since i can't actually
my computer i ca like it's even if i go
down it's going to go down and like i
can't just scroll so
maybe adrian you should share your
screen
is what i'm trying to say
don't have access to it then i will put
it in
our
yeah so we have the assets there there's
three currently there's the
the togethertech.org domain name um
and any current website under there
there's the facebook group and the
youtube channel
i guess we also have a github
while no do we we don't have a
organization yet not for taking the tech
right yeah that's going to be kind of
weird here is figuring out all those
blurred lines where it's like
uh sort of you know a sibling project
has the resource
how is that
yeah so maybe you guys are really just
stewarding those assets on behalf of
a greater community who has yet to be
determined and you're creating the space
for them to be able to join
the stewardship of these assets i mean
maybe that's it for now until you get
more clarity
right sure something like that so
really um that's what this sets up
that's the idea of what you know
co-governance
code gov and what protocol dot love
specifies is the means to share
is how do you steward assets of those
are the assets are stewarding
who has influence over what happens to
those assets
so um generally um it's called the
primary council will be the
you know in the in the technical
specifications for the interfaces i'll
be building
um when you create a collective there's
automatically going to be
a primary council created and
and in order to have
for for individuals to have a say on the
primary council they need to have
influence currency so an influence
currency will automatically be created
so those kind of things are
kind of just things we can write down
and think they're
probably already on there in some form
depending on which version of the
template you grabbed
but it'll be uh
if it's if we scroll up a little bit um
yeah right okay we did some of that cool
so the four of you all have 111
primary council influence currency um
[Music]
and how others can obtain is join the
facebook group keep showing up
on facebook friday meetings
and then if a current influence currency
holder will propose assigning influence
currency to
a member who's been showing up whenever
it
feels organic
and i think the last week we talked
about sort of having two councils
where like anybody you know can sort of
show up to to these meetings and you get
you know your currency in like a
secondary council
or certain decisions would be made by by
those councils
or by that council and then more more
people can be
a part of that and that's probably the
more open one and then there
there there need to be some sort of
criteria for joining the primary council
probably based on how much you've
interacted at the secondary council
level
so you can't just stockpile currency you
actually have to interact and vote and
do things
and then at a certain point it'll be
like hey that person
has been really you know contributing to
the secondary council
let's bring them over cool you could do
it like that generally a council is
uh an entity that's going to steward a
set of assets so right
um what you might be talking more of uh
in the protocol that love ontology is
uh equity currency which is just a
contribution
right you're contributing in some way
that we want to recognize so you might
just be talking about an equity currency
um you know meeting time equity currency
or whatever that or something like that
um so you can write that in there and
you can say
you know assign one one unit for every
hour of
collective meetings somebody shows up
for something like that
obviously i'm just making stuff up so
whatever's right
i i mean that sounds right like that
sounds but i think
the the question that that came out of
was uh uh
around like how does somebody actually
join the primary council like do they
just show up to the meetings
how do they ask right is it just on day
one they have the
the you know the the same number of of
um
well you can be as specific as you want
um it says there
how others can receive right there right
so my point was just the secondary
council came out of that conversation
on the like how and when do do we we
want to add the currency like is it just
you show up and you get one point
and then i think that's when we started
to talk about an alternate you know
council that you can just show up and
get points in
and that might be where we vote on like
you know updates to the website or
something like that but like major
changes to
you know like do we want to change our
our domain name do we want to switch
over to using this platform instead of
that platform
that might be a primary council thing
like sort of the
the really sweeping changes to assets
and then just the smaller like hey what
do we
want to do with this what what do you
think this page on the the website
should look like
that's more open that's the
the thought i had but definitely
interested to hear from julian bentley
on that
i'm wondering what like you were like
well this is clearly this this is
clearly that that is not as clear
like i wouldn't know whether changing
the website design
is a big one or a small one like that
would mean to be more
more put out but i think that they're
more actually this is primary and this
is
this is secondary i do like the idea of
there being
a type of counsel anyone can show up to
and anyone can be part of but you don't
yet know whether you're part of the
primary until you've proven that you're
here week after week
and once that you work well with the
other primary council members right so
to me
it's like anyone can be part of this
secondary if we're using that language
and then um what what does it then look
like for us to allow somebody into
primary is it the primary who votes on
it it has to be unanimous does it have
to be
three quarters like what is it actually
get that person there do we wait until
we have that person to decide it
because then that's going to bring up
more attention than like hey we already
said it had to be unanimous and
one of us said no we're not gonna tell
you who but one of us said no right but
there's
okay when in my interpretation what you
have written here a lot of that's
already
specified um it's what it's saying is
a a pcic holder a current influencing
currency holder
will propose so that means we're making
a proposal and that means that
proposal can be um positively resolved
at which time you would assign the
currency to the new member
so that's all kind of in there because
the proposal resolution process we may
or may not have already specified they
don't remember it's
it's it's down a little further in the
document
nope we haven't so that's where you
would so so generally so
um the proposal would be hey let's
change the website in this way
a proposal would be hey let's buy a new
domain name a proposal would be hey
let's add this person to the primary
council these are all just different
proposals
that could be made and so how you make
those proposals how you
iterate or discuss those proposals and
how you resolve those proposals or what
you would specify there
is probably the the same answer for all
those things to keep it simple now if
you do want to have two different
methodologies for different types of
things then yeah you would want
different councils
to have two different decision making
methodologies
but it seems to me like you're you could
pretty easily get away with
keeping it simple for now if you wanted
to do and having one decision making
methodology for for all those things
simple like we're going to keep it
simple come on
that's ridiculous but there's something
um coming
up which is just that um for the when
somebody is on the primary council
the way that it's worded now is like we
have 111 of these
these currencies and they're every time
they show up they get more and i don't
know how bentley and adrian feel erratic
when he's here but like
to me when someone's part of the primary
council once they're
yes they're on it they have equal say to
everybody else and it's not
right like that is part of having a
secondary is that you have accrued maybe
these points with meeting
and then when you're you voted in yes
you're an equal member it's not you know
well you're a secondary member because
you came on a year later and we already
had 50 hours of meetings
there's that that piece again yeah i
think
just from a definition standpoint when
you say counsel if you mean
what i mean by what protocol.love
proposes as to what council means it
means a group of people that hold
influence a certain amount of influence
currency they make that make decisions
over a set of assets
right so if there's another set of
assets that you want to break out or
which is a subset of what you already
have listed that you want a different
council to steward
then i would say yes start talking about
a second second council
if you're really just trying to give
people an acknowledgement
for the way they should for showing up
to meetings then i think the equity
currency would suffice in that instance
sorry to cut you off adriel no that's
fine that's
that that's helpful um and so i guess
the question
is if we wanted to go the secondary
council route
what would they be doing like well
is it just gagio do you have a reason to
have a secondary council
um i just like do we have secondary
assets to manage
i'm more thinking about that for like
the smaller changes and when we actually
want
like this is assuming that you know
actually start to get more and more
people involved you know and like people
start showing up to five right
yeah and i would say let's do that when
we have
enough people to worry about it and
let's not we'll
talk about that more now part of that is
to build a system to what gets somebody
to the primary council
and i don't know part of my goal as a
stepping stone
so what what ray is saying is that you
don't use a council to step to a council
you use equity currency to step to a
council well he's saying how councils
and currencies are normally used in
that model which is different from
saying we can't do it
i'm not saying we can't do it but but
there's no reason to do it there's no
reason to have a secondary council's a
step to the primary council
that i agree but we just need different
language
like we just need so there's only a
primary council
when you're on it you have equal say to
everybody else right
how do you get to the primary council
right you start you come you
get some kind of currency once you get x
amount of currency you can then
possibly get on the primary we have a
system of you're all going to vote it's
going to be unanimous i'm just
saying that is possibility right and
then you're on it and then you're gonna
be equal
but to get there you can't show up to
day one and we vote right like it's like
okay what are our criteria you come to
ten you come to two
you know what i mean and then um do we
need a unanimous vote do we need a
what if somebody stops showing up right
what if i don't come anymore but i'm not
there to vote right like how many
when do you fall off of the primary
council when do you right and what's
quorum and
all that kind of thing
yes so
we might want to try to do the decision
making methodology before you decide
this perhaps
just so you know what you're talking
about because with the decision-making
methodology then yeah the proposal can
be hey let's bring on joe
to the primary council and give him uh
10 influence currency
or 111 influence currents whatever it
may be but you'll
but you'll understand what that process
would look like then
yes so that is further down
that's the proposal and that part right
that's right methodology
duration yeah so this basically just
protocol.love
proposes that no matter how you go about
making decisions three fundamental
things always happen
somebody initiates a proposal there are
one there are zero or more iterations on
that proposal that is discussions or
changes to it and then at some point you
resolve it by saying
okay let's get into action now or let's
table this we're not going to talk about
it anymore
so how do you go about doing those
things and the
goal here is not to invent some perfect
governance methodology
um the goal is to keep it simple
if that's possible for now um to just
recognize what you've been doing write
it down
and then if you want to change it you
have a framework within which to change
it
because a proposal can be change the
proposal initiation methodology
right
so it seems like if i had to guess
showing up on these meetings doing
having a verbal discussion and everybody
going yep that sounds good to me
is kind of how it goes so basically the
initiation is attend a board reading and
bring up a new
topic i guess and present your proposal
yep like something like proposals are
made um
on live video conferences
and then you might want to specify
somebody mentioned quorum like how many
people need to be present right
um do we want quorum 4
initiation or just for resolution like
if we think that something is you know
like
if i'm gone one week and you know anne
radick isn't here so it's just julian
bentley
julie has an idea and her and bentley
talk about it for 10 or 15 minutes and
say cool let's bring that up next time
it can still be
initiated possibly even iterated just
not voting on it and probably won't be
the final iteration but i think those
first two don't need quorum
but again interested to hear what you've
done yeah since everything's recorded
that should be fine also true
um do you think it's good to actually
call out the areas where there is no
quorum
just to be explicit
you mean like what we can't do unless
there's like just you know
attend board meeting and present
proposal to group and audience
no minimum quorum needed right or no
quorum levels at here or or something
like that
so it's clear or or maybe
quorum is two i was gonna say yeah i'll
just show up
and like propose all my all my ideas
oh yeah i mean you could just record the
video and you primarily watch it later
i yeah i i would just say for you know
obvious sakes i i'm not just going to
attend and talk to myself
for 10 minutes um and then we'll also
say that like
for now they have to be primary council
members in order for it to count
as like but really you know if jubilee
shows up and
carrie shows up and they have a
conversation i mean you know we can
still count
either that or we can count the next
time when we're all here and julie
brings up the
the thing that her and kerry talked
about then it ends up being fine too
so yeah that's a good point right
because that yeah
any two people having a conversation is
already quorum even if it's not fridays
at noon and like hey
as long as that as long as you
understand you have to reiterate it here
and that is part of it is yeah that
that's
don't talk to anyone outside of this
we've done as a family
uh so iteration um i'm not sure what
really needs to be here like it's you
know
well i i i guess like practice omega
rule is probably a good
thing here i'm not sure if we want to
put that in there but like
some element or is that just a general
rule for the primary council
just everything
yeah i don't think we need to get that
little detail that'll
be our common way of doing that
that's also more than continue
without your face it's harder to know
when you're talking about
i was going to say that for iterations i
know i could iterate till the cows come
home
um that that's not actually helpful it's
like hey
here's the initiation and then the
iteration
is like not just can you come up with
something different
is there something that is kind of
equally as good that you can iterate
right is this an improvement
or is it just are you just saying things
yeah or based on how we are as humans
and
what we do so far it could also be that
we need that
right we need 10 15 minutes to go over
any iteration
let's get a unicorn let's get a dragon
and then um
are we back here's the original one
where anything that came out of that is
good
secondary iteration or you know however
many we
we need to be able to do that
i'm good with either having that
brainstorm is part of our normal
and then sometimes it could be like well
it doesn't make sense to have a
brainstorm for this one
it doesn't make sense okay i guess
another part of this that's tied to sort
of the first thing is where does this
live
like i we kind of do meeting minutes but
not really
i wonder if we've like kind of started
doing them properly on like okay here's
the minutes for this date
you know jubilees you know submitted the
proposal for x
as a part or sorry she initiated the
here's that part of the the discussion
um
and then to keep it easy we just keep
everything in the the minutes
at some point you probably want like a
separate place where the proposals live
you can say here's
this proposal that julie made here's it
being initiated here's iteration one two
and three
here's the final iteration and here's
how the vote went can you guys hear me
yep okay good all right i was trying to
talk earlier i don't think he could
all right so a couple things here
obviously people just having
conversations anytime
uh in their lives uh isn't a proposal
but what happens is that that same
conversation is had
in the meeting on the zoom call what
you're calling a board meeting which you
might want to just define exactly what
that means
um then that is a proposal and so
um yeah so to your point adriel
definitely what a lot of groups have
done
um is they just there's no documentation
required for the proposal
there's no documentation required for
the iteration but on the resolution
you go and do your best to recruit to
reconstruct when it was initiated by who
what iterations were there any
dissenting sorry sorry to interrupt you
raymond are you aware your camera is
still on
we can hear you we're all so quiet
i'm just putting a belt on there's
nothing weird it's all good i didn't
know if you knew that was all
i was like does this supposed to get a
little more or less keep going keep
going sorry to interrupt you
yeah all right cool um so yeah uh
so that's that's what a lot of groups do
you just document it all on resolution
and then you can just have a google doc
that you can even link to
right in your resolutions methodology
section you can point right to that
google doc
that's one way to do it okay um
i like that as sort of like the the bare
bones no matter what we have to have it
documented when
we're resolving it because then where
does it go otherwise hey didn't we talk
about
changing something two weeks ago what
what do we do to
doing about that um i am wondering if
just
it doesn't seem like these meetings i
mean especially me
are terribly organized so i wondered if
the if we did want to say like
ideally if you want to have a proposal
so we can sort of see like how it's
changed and you know who proposed it and
how old it is and stuff like that
um if we want to start out with just a
really
basic like one proposal document and
then you know if we're talking about a
proposal in a meeting we do a screen
share like this where it's kind of meant
to like take notes and
as i do find that doing something like
this where we actually have a document
that we're all working off of
keeps things on track way better when
we're like okay so this sentence here
you know is what we just come up with
okay well what do you mean by
you know by board meeting or what do you
mean by this and you can start to sort
of
work it out and then at the end we've
got notes of what we were doing
because there have been quite a few
meetings where we come back what were we
talking about last time
we talked about something like this or
was that two two sessions ago
i feel like what might work for us i
don't know how to put it in here
is um where we did have that
was even called like what we were gonna
talk about right and we pulled it up
every time we never had it on the screen
right having something like that that is
very
um like sort of first draft start with
an agenda and have that turn into the
minutes
kind of like meaning sorry whatever we
have the same thing we had before
it's chaotic it's messy we don't
necessarily keep it up but when we
resolve something we have kind of a good
version that that is what we absolutely
do so even if the other one falls apart
and the other one
you know what i mean we don't we're
talking about omni when the definition
for three day for three sessions
when we resolve something that goes on
and possibly even a spreadsheet for
those initiations of proposals of like
every proposal initiated and just where
it stands right did we resolve it
did we did we table it like what
actually
happened um because that's part of the
resolution right there ones that kind of
like well i don't know did we end up
finishing that sentence did we
actually talk about that right like the
rough copy
and then like the because i i think
we can keep one good document and put on
resolutions i think we can manage
that that's different and the nice thing
about that is because it's a spreadsheet
and for doing it with a google doc
you can then have have also links like
if you have a different
document per resolution or you know like
or sorry per
proposal or maybe only when it gets to
resolution either way
once it has a document you can stick it
in that sheet you can see here's the
the proposal here's where it's at here's
when it was done there's no document yet
oh there is no great stick it in that
spreadsheet and then that's the one list
that
how's that i like it
i'm not sure how that fits into this
spot
i almost wonder if we need
we're going to try to document the
initiation the iterations but what we're
really going to document is the
resolution
is what i think we can write down like a
good copy resolution where you can
follow through what happened on this
meeting what happened on this meeting
and
a here's where our marketing proposal
stands or here's where our
um now i guess part of the question is
if we
vote on a resolution that fails and
we're like look you know we're gonna
stop talking about this
we probably don't need a full resolution
document i guess it's just if we're
saying yes
or is it also if we're saying no that we
feel like we still want to go and
if properly a resolution i feel it's a
resolution it's either we voted yes we
voted no
or we voted to table it because it was
too much conflict but we're going to
reiterate it we're going to come back to
this
x amount or we're not going to come back
to it it was two it's too
too difficult
yeah i can recommend some wording for
you if you want sure
yeah it sounds like on a proposal
initiation you just
say proposals are initiated
when at least two
pcic holders are present
on
not
sorry proposals are initiated when at
least two pcic holders are present in
interactive video meetings
so i'm so this is under initiation
methodology right yes
um so proposals are initiated when
yeah like that those are initiated when
at least two pcic members are present in
an interactive video meeting and that
gives us quorum as well
right you can use the quorum if you want
no that's fine i like to stick to things
it's
possible and then i think i think it's
the same for an iteration proposals are
iterated when it's two pc i
see two pcic holders are present in an
interactive video meeting
and then a resolution you just say
uh proposals are resolved when at least
or what are you doing you'll be doing
back in census
yeah what are we doing for actual like
to pass something how much
does it have to pass by
i guess we probably want to use
percentages i'm guessing so like as
things grow
so if yeah yeah
we could always change it later right
now we could say consensus meaning
everyone
there has to be no dissenters right i
don't know
how do you normally phrase that right um
well yeah if you want consensus then
when uh proposals are
uh positively resolved when 100 percent
of pcic holders
or 100 percent of pcic
desires it so
okay and then uh i always try
i never use the word vote but that's
just me okay
uh then you know upon positive
resolution
uh you know the
all details of the initiation and
iterations are recorded
along with the details of the proposal
of you know something like that whatever
details of the proposal
when it was initiated by who what it was
iterated by who
um
and that should pretty much do it that
you know you could like i said you could
actually create a blank
uh google doc right now and link to it
right in there doc
right here in this resolution
methodology section
um and for the resolution i i i i guess
we said all bcsc holders so that is the
quorum is everyone full resolutions i
guess we're saying
yeah we should probably like everyone
who's present
everyone who like that is part of the
like like right now radix
here right so are we we're
we don't do anything because he's not
here how does that actually
yeah i i guess that that's true oh
that's wording it so that yeah you
couldn't act
it's yes super choppy but yeah yeah
because it's saying all pcic holders
so it's not saying all them present it's
saying all of them so there's two pieces
out beholders all of them have to vote
with this current
everyone present with this is something
like this
everyone present can vote and then
they're the people who aren't present
have an option to initiate a proposal to
undo it right to be like hey
actually i wasn't here and i'm really
not okay with what you guys decided
is like a new proposal initiation
iteration resolution
like you're we're all fully allowed to
make decisions without everybody present
but if we have those those quora members
someone can come in and be
like it's like a red card in consensus
like you don't come in and do that for
oh i don't know i don't really know if i
like my phones right
what is quorum for that number though
well since we're saying we're doing
consensus one person saying hey i don't
like what you guys decided this isn't
big enough i would have read flagged
this
right no sorry i mean like if we have 10
council members how many have to be
there in order for us like
if we're saying you can change it later
great but if there's ten people and two
of you have a meeting and you have
consensus
that that that won't count right like
quorum is how many people of the overall
body have to be there for us to even
consider voting
like if there's three out of 10 don't
even bother voting because you can't
like it won't do anything gotcha 70 i
for me i'm to say 75
is quorum of people present and for
resolutions
they can't take place at any other time
besides our friday meet right that like
you can
like us meeting over things we could do
that but we can't
come to a conclusion until it's actually
part of the meeting right
okay so we can initiate it and we can
iterate it
we just as long as there's at least two
but then to actually resolve it
we have to have quorum of at least 75
percent of the pci see holders present
and of those people there has to be a
consensus
75 present and it has to be during this
friday meeting right or if we move the
friday meeting it's like
at an official meeting as opposed to
whatever for now i'm just i'm not going
to try to word it properly i'm just
going to say quorum is now do want 75
or 66 yeah just as the two sort of
standard
if if you just say 75 have to agree
it's an assumption when you say that
that that's a quorum
you know what i'm saying you know that's
duplicating language to say they have to
be proven
different from they can't agree if
they're not there they totally
disagree right like quorum is you don't
even vote at all so
right there are different terms but by
saying that that they have to agree
they have to be there to agree so you
have to have that as a quorum
so what i'm saying is a quorum for
discussion but a vote it's just a
percentage of votes
they have to be there to vote so you
don't have to say both
right but we're talking about changing
one of them right if we're saying only
of the people have to be present like in
that meeting for us to vote on it
do those all have to agree because then
that's two different things it's
saying there's no reason to say those
two different
i'm just saying it's over complicating
it to say anything other than
let's not say how many people have to be
there or quorum just say how many people
have to agree
seventy-five percent after are you
saying if someone's present and they
disagree even though you have 75 percent
then it won't happen that's why i'm
trying to express that's what we've been
saying so far is like
if anybody votes there has to be a
hundred percent
consensus among those who vote and then
the quorum is
yeah are we going to bother if only two
out of 10 people are voted we don't care
if it's 100 of them because it's only 20
of the total council
our decision-making methodology still
need to call out
and quorum is 75 so we can't really even
resolve
anything if there aren't at least 75 of
us 75
of us present but then we are having a
discussion
to get to consensus we do have to have a
resolution what happens when we can't
come to consensus
right and that will be well yes okay
well red car
green card yellow card are we leaving
because there's a conflict like
what does that look like against this
right and i know radick had said at the
end of the last time right that that was
his
his like no i want to come to consensus
and i think we're all
that's what we've been doing so far
anyway um
and there's a little bit of like when we
first come to our first conflict
that what then happens right then it is
partly a resolution of what happens when
we can't come to a consensus on an idea
but that's different than quorum quorums
just how many people need to be present
for us to
come to a consensus at all yeah for us
to even try
right right i'm just right right just
ignore what i said because that was i
didn't
realize that someone could be present
and and and disagree with it and then it
won't pass
even if you have the 75 percent right so
that's uh that's not
you know i hadn't thought about how
consensus works that way yeah
right right so yeah 75 quorum and then
consensus of the people present
okay i would i would recommend not using
the word quorum because if you do you
need to define what that means but just
say it so um
75 of the people present yeah i guess
yeah members pcs holders yeah whatever
then uh but what i was actually
suggesting in that first
wording we used was i said uh 100 of
pcic holders
desire to be so um so that doesn't
require them to be present on the
meeting that means like you could all
agree on the meeting and
and uh uh it was the other fella who's
not there
uh you could say hey i'll check with him
offline and if he says
yeah then i'll record that and i'll
mention i'll put that
mention that i did that and well well
yeah what we don't want is if someone
falls off the face of the earth and just
leaves the project
we we don't want to have to be held up
by them yeah which is likely to happen
in an open project like this especially
as the numbers grow right if we if we
have
accounts of 10 people
that can get out of control pretty fast
yep and so then you could have an
exception for that you know
uh if if a member is unreachable
we'll do xyz and then assume that they
approve
right yeah yeah so that's basically what
we have except we're putting the onus on
them to
to attend the meeting yeah and then if
it went on a super long time we might
have a proposal
to remove them that they will have to be
present for but we all have to agree
so you know if jubilee disappears for
two months and we're starting to talk
about it
but you know i know that she's doing
something i don't agree then like
it wouldn't be if we all agreed like
yeah she's been gone she's been m.i.a
see you later then she'd be removed
just like for any of us um
okay so you'd be in the same 22 with a
proposal to remove somebody's pcic
if it's 100 consensus so it seems like
the simplest thing might be to leave
kind of something like that a rich
wording but just have an exception that
if if a board member is unreachable
is unable to be communicated with then
you're going to do these this procedure
and if none of that works then you
temporarily remove their pcic or
something
right well i i think
the wording we have gets at the same
yeah i think we would then be able to
introduce whatever
we wanted as a proposal in these these
situations so right now we've got at
least 75 percent of pcic
holders uh must be present to hold a
vote and there must be
consensus uh let's say to
resolve it to
this is another reason i don't use the
word vote
because it's just really to me like to
really boil it down
you just want approval from x number of
people or approval from
x amount of pcic okay uh so
you receive google from everyone right
that means if somebody
doesn't want it to go fast
so what do we call the the session that
that happens like usually you'd say to
hold a vote
to ask for approval
if you hold a vote then you have to
define all the things about what that is
you can it just like again
i'm not saying i disagree i'm just like
can it just become
a consensus at least 75 percent of pcic
holders must be present to come to a
consensus sure yeah
what two positive results is that what
you mean come to a
consensus on a resolution so at least 75
percent of pcic holders must be present
to come to a consensus on resolution
okay so you have to say there's no one
expressing dissent
i think because that kind of implies you
could have 75 percent people agree and
you could do it
but if we want to explicitly say if
someone truly agrees it doesn't happen
yeah it's implied no you don't want no
dissenting opinions you don't want to
imply
something like this you want to explicit
so yeah i agree
um with no dissenting opinions would
probably do it
that's part yeah okay but this part of
consensus is like whatever our consensus
process
is it should be obvious whether
somebody's in opposition
whether they're like in between like uh
i would but i'm gonna let you guys go
with it
um versus for it right and that is kind
of the
like you're not voting you're green
carding red carding whatever our thing
is
and red card is like you're definitely
not in consensus and
leaving over it right and yellow so yeah
but it's interesting right i see so i
mean it sounds a bit like
sort of yellow is abstaining red is like
no
although i guess yellow is also a soft
no it's just like i don't want it but i
don't care that much so if you go ahead
with it
you know i'm not going to be i'm just
using the the terminology
when i was doing this i like that the
idea right because not all nodes are
what's that what's all the what's the
rag flag
called it's not no right it's a it's
objecting right
um there's so if i'd have to remember
but while we were doing it it was like
is there talking about right are we
gonna get another dishwasher are we
gonna do this are we gonna do that
you're
you're you're let's say right at the
beginning you vote and someone might
have a
the red cards and yellow cards mean
something different you're saying yes or
no just just in this to start the
conversation because if everyone's okay
with the dishwasher why are we even
having a conversation
so you're saying yes or no but you're
not leaving or staying based on it
and then you have yellow's like i need
way more information like what
dishwasher
why are we needing it why are we and
then you you
wait until all the yellow cards are kind
of resolved and so you've talked about
all those things this is like with a
much bigger than four of us right
it's like with 50 of us and and then
when you're voting voting
red card means i'm leaving over this if
you guys go forward with this i'm
leaving yellow's like
you heard me you know i object to it but
i'll stay even if you guys choose the
other way and green is like yes
dishwasher right so
it's it's making that obvious
the word i was thinking of was block
block yeah that's the red card is block
in that yeah so no one blocks the
resolution
because there's not because there's no
leaving and staying you know that's not
that's not terminology for what we're
doing it's yes
it's allowing or blocking
holders blocking okay
you guys could write all that out right
now
but you wanted all that well i don't
think we want to get into
yeah i i don't i don't think we have to
get in that level of detail just as long
as we know what word
means someone's expressly
yeah i think as long as i people is
blocking so i think that's clear right
and as long as we're setting up this
initial system to support
you know a system where we can make
whatever changes we we
we need as long as you know we're coming
to some form of a consensus
i that's good so you know i i think
anyone here thinks that this is perfect
but it gives us the roadmap to say well
i have these changes i want to make so i
can make proposals and go through it and
we can have that
discussion on how to change this and of
course we haven't signed anything yet so
if next week you say actually i came up
with a better idea then we can talk
about that
but for now i think that this works as a
good model for
yeah there's also four of us we don't
need cards when there's four of us
it's more when there's you know what i
mean it's like we don't want to be like
adrenal how do you feel bentley how do
you feel it's like you just
show the cards um it just makes it
easier however
yes here we're going to be talking
you're going to know who's blocking your
you know like
i don't feel comfortable with this yet
we still need to deal with this and
we'll come to a point when when
no resolution still a resolution and we
still have to come to something right
yep
i think that that that makes sense and
then odds are
we'll probably end up with some kind of
like a backlog of like proposals that
some people like some people didn't and
we might want to massage them in the
future but for now we'll drop it
yeah so it sounds like you can keep it
really simple
in your resolution process
so let me actually move this part up
here
because if like if you just say that
everybody has to
copy yeah i see
get there right but the bottom agreed
can anyone else cut out a bunch it's not
just me
yeah couldn't quite hear you but yes
where i think we're
we're good with what it's at at the
moment
okay so here i
i guess we can go through it all because
it's fairly short so the initiation
methodology is proposals are initiated
when at least two pcic holders are
present
in an interactive video meeting the
iteration methodology
uh proposals are iterated when at least
two pcic holders are present in an
interactive video meeting the resolution
methodology
at least 75 percent of pcic holders must
be present
to come to a consensus on a resolution
with no holders blocking
upon positive resolution all details of
the
initiation and iterations are recorded
along with the the the details of the
i'm going to say final proposal um
details should include who initiated the
proposal the iterations and participated
in the resolution
that sounds good uh my question is um
what do we mean by interactive video
meeting
because i feel that actually like does
that mean that
people can watch it that it has to be
public or does it mean that it's
recorded so other people can watch it
later
right it might be private it might be
unlisted and then
you might be like i feel like a recorded
video meeting
is more i also kind of just feel like
board meeting because if it ends up
being things that were like okay these
two topics we figured out we can't do
publicly
and you know if if we end up doing it on
the phone
if we're just saying in the end it's uh
you know a certain board meeting like if
we're saying that the friday session
regardless if it happens on live stream
or if when we
we do it over the phone the important
thing is that it's the
pcic holders that are there and that
they're voting
yeah i think a video meeting is and a
meeting
recorded meeting even if it's not made
public
we know we have it right like it would
make no sense for adriel and bentley to
have a conversation that's private
where they talked about initiation
iteration resolution
and reddick and i can't see it right
like at least
that maybe that might be the case like
later on i think also
the interactive video meeting is only
mentioned in initiation and iteration
right like so and so i think that's
meant to be vague
so that it's like if we you know do the
project round table and something comes
up there
we can still initiate it and iterate it
there but to actually vote on it or like
to actually have the resolution
we have to bring that to the board
meeting um
so i wonder if in the resolution
methodology we want to
mention the board meeting is like it
happens there um
and or change the wording on interactive
video meetings so that it's not
you know it could just be recorded
theoretically it could just be audio
if push comes to shove it could be me
over jubilee's place
yeah no that's kind of right sometimes
you just have a conversation carrie and
i have conversations and
she's i don't know if she's part of
together tech anymore but like that
right it just kind of comes up and
sometimes we record sometimes we don't
it's like oh yeah that wasn't right
which i guess then
if we're just saying like can you
initiate something
at not a board meeting or does it have
to be initiated like
you can have all the pre-initiation
conversations you want and pre-planning
and do this and
go to town but when you're like hey guys
i have an idea for
together tech could that happen at a
project round table or you know just me
over at jubilee's place or does that
have to happen here think we're saying
it can happen just with you over at my
place because we could do the
but like it's not going to get resolved
until we're again bringing it to the
median and
and everyone else hasn't has an option
of iterating it right
an option of it so it's like yes they'll
be at the board meeting but with the
understanding that it could have come
from somewhere else
and there's a three-hour conversation
you weren't privy to or we did dish
things
out but that doesn't mean that we can
decide on things from that three-hour
conversation
right that whatever was there has to be
brought into
into the conversation to be resolved a
bit
like because if you know if
billy and i went up to the side and had
a bunch of meetings and planned out some
cool stuff and then
like in my mind that's not initiation
yet we're sort of pre-initiation we're
planning hey
for us to initiate this proposal for
together tech let's you know get all our
ducks in a row and and make some images
explaining things and some mock-ups or
whatever else we end up saying is
necessary
now in our minds we might be thinking
okay we're going to show it to
the council everyone is going to agree
and we're going to resolve it
but we still have to go through like
actually initiating it with the council
and then they might have some iterations
it almost seems like if you're not doing
it in front of the council
you may think you're doing a resolution
vote but technically
you're initiating it you might end up
passing but
more often than not there's probably
still going to be iterations at that
point
at that point they should probably be
done through the council right like if
if bentley and i go off and plan and
come and show stuff to the council
and then jubilee and radic are like well
actually let's change this and do that
and do this and and do that instead
to me that sounds like the real
initiation and then
the that's the first also iteration
where we're saying we're initiating it
and then jubilee and radic are saying
well wait hold on this this this now
that's the first iteration all in the
same meeting
yeah you're very right it's just that
let's like it's like
rough draft versus a good draft right if
we have a conversation there's always
going to be initiations and iterations
coming up
but we're not going to officially
initiate and iterate it until we come to
the council and so therefore
the resolutions the piece you have to
bring but in order to bring the
resolution you have to bring the first
two
just we're kind of honoring that that
this is still
like you can still have the initiation
and iteration and initiation and
reiteration all day every day but yeah
until it's officially parted together
tech you're gonna have to bring it to a
meeting we're gonna have to iterate it
anyway and we're gonna resolve it
right i guess i'm just wondering do we
care about that
the initiating and iterating outside of
that because i've got a ton of ideas
that
i might end up proposing that i'll be
initiating and iterating by myself
right and just like going off and
planning things in my mind that doesn't
really count as
initiation it's me just right right
a planning ideas
initiation or iteration it's just here's
how you could
one of the one of your members of your
council or ultimately anybody outside
if you want to operate with complete
transparency here's how you
find out what has been initiated and
iterated right
right so and if there is no specific way
except on a positive resolution that's
fine too at least
i think we're running out of time let me
suggest let me initiate
no suggest uh that we uh that we
think on this maybe we have one meeting
without
taking a braised time and then maybe we
invite him to like every other meeting
let us digest what we discussed
iterate on it once and then have him
back um right
yeah i mean he was quite useful in in
ian's meeting but i felt bad about the
last one because that was
a gong show
and if my memory could remember whether
we invited or not that would be good
you know short notice is fine i'm glad
to be here it's on my calendar
by default so i won't have anything else
scheduled this time generally so
just let me know awesome
sounds good thank you for your time
today we really appreciate all your help
ray
i'm honored to be here thank you guys
all right
see you too bye-bye
all right so we're good we're gonna meet
tomorrow morning for our round table or
tomorrow
different time zones um to discuss our
projects and where we are with them and
then we'll be back next week to
continue on with this unless anyone else
has any clothing statements we can
probably
end the broadcast all right
thank you youtube and facebook see you
tomorrow and then